Guide to the Lillian D. Wald Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
  - Warburg, Felix M. to LDW; [November 1930)-10 Man:h 1933 (Box 12, Folder 73 to 75)
  - Warburg, Felix M., from Henry Street Settlement; 1919-1933 (Box 12, Folder 76)
  - Warburg, Frederick M. to LDW; 10 Man:h 1933 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Warburg, Frieda Schiff (Mrs. Felix M.) to LDW; n.d. -10 March 1933 (Box 12, Folder 1 to 4)
  - Warburg, Max M. to LDW; 6 January 1926 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Warburg, Nina J. Loeb (Mrs. Paul M.) to LDW; n.d. -30 November 1917 (Box 13, Folder 1 to 12)
  - Warburg, Nina J. Loeb (Mrs. Paul M.) to Mrs. Biggs; (1922) (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Warburg, Nina J. Loeb (Mrs. Paul M.) to LDW; 1931 -14 April 1931 (Box 13, Folder 14 to 15)
  - Warburg, Paul Moritz to LDW; IS June 1903 -17 Man:h 1909 (Box 13, Folder 1 to 3)
  - Warburg, Paul Moritz to Viola P. Conklin; 9 March 1914 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Warburg, Paul Moritz to LDW; J June 1914 -22 November 1922 (Box 13, Folder 5 to 7)
  - Warburg, Paul Moritz to Elsa H. Herrmann; 8 March 1923 -23 April 1923 (Box 13, Folder 8 to 9)
  - Warburg, Paul Moritz to LDW; 5 February 1926 -13 January 1931 (Box 13, Folder 10 to 13)
  - Warren, Schuyler N., Jr. to Karl D. Hesley; 27 April 1929 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    On Reel 11 of the Wald Microfilm
  - Welling, Richard Ward Greene to LDW; 19 January 1904 -21 March 1929 (Box 13, Folder 1 to 6)
  - Whalen, Grover A. to LDW; 18 April 1918 -9 December 1927 (Box 13, Folder 1 to 4)
  - White, Gaylord Starin to LDW; 4 May 1906 -19 January 1927 (Box 13, Folder 1 to 11)
  - White, Henry to LDW; 23 September 1904 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Whiteins. Richard to LDW; 3 September 1905 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Whyte, (Sir) Frederick to LDW; 7 June [1926] (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Whyte. Jane Elizabeth Barbour (Mrs. Alexander) to LDW; 30 April 1926 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Wiley, Louis to LDW; 30 April 1925 -26 November 1930 (Box 13, Folder 1 to 5)
  - Wiley. Louis to Basia GruUow; 17 July 1931 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Wiley, Louis to LDW; 9 March 1933 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Wilmowski, Barbara Krupp to LDW; 27 December 1909 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Wise. Stephen Samuel to Alice and Irene Lewisohn; 22 April 1914 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Wise, Stephen Samuel to LDW; 21 April 1916 -IS April 1927 (Box 13, Folder 2 to 8)
  - Wynne, Shirley W. to LDW; 27 May 1931 -27 November 1931 (Box 13, Folder 1 to 4)
  - Young, Stark to LDW; n.d. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Zangwill, Israel to LDW; 18 June 1905 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Series II: Arranged Corresponcence
  - Personal correspondence: A. (Box 14)
  - Personal correspondence: B (Box 14)
  - Personal correspondence; C. (Box 14)
  - Personal correspondence; D (Box 14)
  - Personal correspondence: E (Box 14)
  - Personal correspondence: F (Box 14)
  - Personal correspondence: G (Box 14)
  - Personal correspondence: H (Box 14)
  - Personal correspondence: I (Box 14)
  - Personal correspondence: J (Box 14)
    On Reel 12 of the Wald Microfilm
  - Personal correspondence: K (Box 14)
  - Personal correspondence: L (Box 14)
  - Personal correspondence: M (Box 14)
  - Personal correspondence: N (Box 14)
  - Personal correspondence: O (Box 14)
  - Personal correspondence: P (Box 14)
  - Personal correspondence: R (Box 14)
  - Personal correspondence: S (Box 14)
  - Personal correspondence: T (Box 15, Folder 1)
    On Reel 13 of the Wald Microfilm
  - Personal correspondence: V (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Personal correspondence: W (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Personal correspondence: Waters. Ysabella (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Personal correspondence: X-Z (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - "Get well" letter (A-M), 1925 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - "Get well" letters (N-Z), 1925 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - "Get well" letters (miscellaneous), 1925 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence re. Wald property in Westport, Conn., 1931 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Wald: personal bills, receipts, etc., 1932-33 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    On Reel 14 of the Wald Microfilm
  - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - "Twas the first of July ... " (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - [Tenement houses] (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - District nursing (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - The people who live in tenements (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Theodore Roosevelt -The "Social Worker" (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - The effect of the environment in the development of character (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - The House on Henry Street (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - The House on Henry Street, II Children and play" (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - The House on Henry Street, III Education and the child (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - The House on Henry Street, III Education and. the child (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - The House on Henry Street, IV Children and work (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - The House on Henry Street, V The youth of our neighborhood (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - The House on Henry Street, VI Social forces (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - The House on Henry Street (Notes) (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - The Nursing Service (address) (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Israel (poem) (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Birthday cards, 1933 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Birthday letters, 1933 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    On Reel 15 of the Wald Microfilm
  - Birthday telegrams, 1933 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous manuscripts and documents (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - The Ladies own journal anti-suffrage number (Box 16, Folder 21)
- Series III: General Subjects
  - A (misc.) (Box 17, Folder 1)
    On Reel 15 & 16 of the Wald Microfilm
  - All-American Anti-Imperialist League (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - All Saints’ Church (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - American Civil Liberties Union (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - American Eugenics Society (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - American Humane Society (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - American Indian Defense Association (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - American League to Abolish Capital Punishment (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - American Red Cross (2) (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - American Scandinavian Foundation (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Association for Improving Condition of the Poor (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - B (misc.) (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Birth Control (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Block Community Organization (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Bonfield, Margaret (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Brooklyn Bureau of Charities (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Bryn Mawr (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - C (miscellaneous) (Box 18, Folder 1)
    On Reel 16 of the Wald Microfilm
  - Carnegie Corporation (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - The Catholic Charities of the Archdiocese of New York (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Charity Chest of the Fur Industry (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Charity Organization Society (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Citizenship (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Citizens Union of the City of New York (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Civic Clubs. miscellaneous (Box 18, Folder 8.1)
  - Civic Clubs. East Side Civic Club (Box 18, Folder 8.2)
  - Civic Clubs, New Era Club (Box 18, Folder 8.3)
  - Civic Clubs. Right Hand Club (Box 18, Folder 8.4)
  - Civic Clubs, Social Reform Club (Box 18, Folder 8.5)
  - College Arts Association Exhibit. 1933 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Civic Committee for Adult Literacy (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Committee for the Prevention of Blindness; formation, 1908 (Box 18, Folder 11.1)
  - Committee for the Prevention of Blindness. National Committee (Box 18, Folder 11.2)
  - Committee for the Prevention of Blindness. New York State Committee (Box 18, Folder 11.3)
  - Committee for the Prevention of Blindness; reports, minutes, printed material (Box 18, Folder 11.4)
  - Community Church (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Commonwealth Fund (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - The Community Council. St. Louis (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Community Councils. Bridge District (Box 19, Folder 1.1)
    On Reel 17 of the Wald Microfilm
  - Community Councils, City Parliament (Box 19, Folder 1.2)
  - Community Councils, Lower East Side Community Council (Box 19, Folder 1.3)
  - Community Councils, miscellaneous (Box 19, Folder 1.4)
  - Community Councils; reports, etc. (Box 19, Folder 1.5)
  - Conference of Charities and Correction. National (Box 19, Folder 2.1)
  - Conference of Charities and Correction. New York City (Box 19, Folder 2.2)
  - Conference of Charities and Correction. New York State (Box 19, Folder 2.3)
  - Consumers and Producers Foundation (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Consumers League (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Correlated Graphic Industries (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Council on Adult Education for the Foreign-Born (Box 19, Folder 6)
    On Reel 18 of the Wald Microfilm
  - Crain, Thomas C. T. (Campaign for District Attorney) (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Crime, general (Box 19, Folder 8.1)
  - Crime, Society for the Prevention of Crime: 1 (Box 19, Folder 8.2)
  - Crime, Society for the Prevention of Crime: 2 (Box 19, Folder 8.3)
  - Crime, Society for the Prevention of Crime: 3 (Box 19, Folder 8.4)
  - Crowdy, (Dame) Rachel (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - D (miscellaneous) (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Dewey, John; birthday celebration. 1929 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - "The Double Star" (magazine) (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - E (miscellaneous) (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - East Side Chamber of Commerce (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Encyclopedia Britannica (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - English-Speaking Union (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Federal Council of Churches (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Fire Protection (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Foreign Affairs Forum (Box 20, Folder 10)
    On Reel 19 of the Wald Microfilm
  - Foreign Language Information Service, correspondence (Box 20, Folder 11.1)
  - Foreign Language Information Service. releases (Box 20, Folder 11.2)
  - Foreign Policy Association, correspondence (Box 20, Folder 12.1)
  - Foreign Policy Association; releases, etc.: 1 (Box 20, Folder 12.2)
  - Foreign Policy Association; releases. etc.: 2 (Box 20, Folder 12.3)
  - Foreign Relief (post-World War I) (Box 21, Folder 1.1)
  - Foreign Relief (post-World War I), German (Box 21, Folder 1.2)
  - "The Forum-(magazine) (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - G (miscellaneous) (Box 21, Folder 3)
    On Reel 20 of the Wald Microfilm
  - German Student Movement (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Goldman, Emma (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Harmon Foundation, Jedidiah Tingle (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Haven Country Club (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Havens Relief Fund (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Hospitals (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Hospital Saturday and Sunday Association (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Housing, correspondence (Box 21, Folder 11.1)
  - Housing, correspondence (City Housing Corporation) (Box 21, Folder 11.2)
  - Housing, correspondence (Housekeeping Centers) (Box 21, Folder 11.3)
  - Housing, correspondence (New York State and Municipal) (Box 21, Folder 11.4)
  - Housing, correspondence (Regional planning) (Box 21, Folder 11.5)
  - Housing, correspondence (tenements) (Box 21, Folder 11.6)
  - Housing, clippings (Box 22, Folder 1.1)
    On Reel 21 of the Wald Microfilm
  - Housing; pamphlets, etc. (Box 22, Folder 1.2)
  - Housing; reports. etc. (Box 22, Folder 1.3)
  - Housing; reports. etc. (mimeographs) (Box 22, Folder 1.4)
  - Housing, Janitors' Society (Box 22, Folder 2.1)
  - Housing, New York City transportation problem (Box 22, Folder 2.2)
  - Housing, regional plan of New York City and its environs. (correspondence) (Box 22, Folder 2.3)
  - Housing, regional plan of New York City and its environs. (printed material) (Box 22, Folder 2.4)
  - Housing, regional plan of New York City and its environs, (reports) (Box 22, Folder 2.5)
  - The Humanitarian Cult (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - I (miscellaneous) (Box 23, Folder 1)
    On Reel 22 of the Wald Microfilm
  - Immigration. Correspondence: 1 (Box 23, Folder 2.1)
  - Immigration, correspondence: 2 (Box 23, Folder 2.2)
  - Immigration, deportation (Box 23, Folder 2.3)
  - Immigration, Federal Government (Box 23, Folder 2.4)
  - Immigration, New York State Commission of Immigration (Box 23, Folder 2.5)
  - Immigration, New York State Department of Labor (Box 23, Folder 2.6)
  - Immigration. printed materials (clippings) (Box 23, Folder 2.7)
  - Immigration, printed materials (pamphlets) (Box 23, Folder 2.8)
  - Immigration, reports (Box 23, Folder 2.9)
  - India (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Institute of International Education (Box 23, Folder 4)
    On Reel 23 of the Wald Microfilm
  - Insurance. Group Insurance (Box 23, Folder 5.1)
  - Insurance. Metropolitan Life Insurance Co. (Box 23, Folder 5.2)
  - International Press (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - J (miscellaneous) (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Jewish matters, general (Box 24, Folder 2.1)
  - Jewish matters. Hebrew Technical School (Box 24, Folder 2.2)
  - Jewish matters. Palestine (Box 24, Folder 2.3)
  - Jewish philanthropic organizations, miscellaneous (Box 24, Folder 3.1)
  - Jewish philanthropic organizations, United Jewish Aid Societies of Brooklyn (Box 24, Folder 3.2)
  - Jewish Philanthropic Societies. Federation for the Support of (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Jewish publications (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Jewish Social Research. Bureau of (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Jewish Social Service Association (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Jewish Vacation Committee (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Joint Board of Sanitary Control. correspondence (Box 24, Folder 9.1)
    On Reel 24 of the Wald Microfilm
  - Joint Board of Sanitary Control, correspondence reo Kingston? N.Y. sanitorium (Box 24, Folder 9.2)
  - Joint Board of Sanitary Control; minutes, reports, etc. (Box 24, Folder 9.3)
  - Joint Board of Sanitary Control. printed materials (Box 24, Folder 9.4)
  - Joint Vocational Service (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - L (miscellaneous) (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Lavanburg Foundation (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - League of Women Voters (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Legislation (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - M (miscellaneous) (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - McCann Relief Fund (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Mental health (Box 25, Folder 7.1)
  - Mental health, reports: 1917-1920 (Box 25, Folder 7.2)
    On Reel 25 of the Wald Microfilm
  - Mental health, reports: 1922-1924 (Box 25, Folder 7.3)
  - Mental retardation (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Milbank Memorial Fund (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Milk (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Milk Commission, correspondence (Box 26, Folder 3.1)
    On Reel 26 of the Wald Microfilm
  - Milk Commission, reports: I (Box 26, Folder 3.2)
  - Milk Commission, reports: 2 (Box 26, Folder 3.3)
  - Milk Commission, clippings (Box 26, Folder 3.4)
  - Mooney, Tom (Defense Committee) (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Music (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Music The People's Chorus of New York (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Musicians' Emergency Aid of New York (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - N (miscellaneous) (Box 27, Folder 1)
    On Reel 27 of the Wald Microfilm
  - National Institute of Social Services (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - "The Nation" (magazine) (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Negroes, correspondence (Box 27, Folder 4.1)
  - Negroes, memoranda (Box 27, Folder 4.2)
  - Negros, printed materials (Box 27, Folder 4.3)
  - Negroes, at the Henry Street Settlement (Box 27, Folder 4.4)
  - Negroes. N.A.A.C.P. (Box 27, Folder 4.5)
  - Negroes, National Health Circle (Box 27, Folder 4.6)
  - Negroes, National Interracial Conference (Box 27, Folder 4.7)
  - New York. (committees, organizations, etc.) (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - New York City, departments (miscellaneous) (Box 27, Folder 6.1)
  - New York City, Board of Education: 1 (Box 27, Folder 6.2)
  - New York City, Board of Education: 2 (Box 27, Folder 6.3)
    On Reel 28 of the Wald Microfilm
  - New York City, Board of Education: Continuation Schools (Box 27, Folder 6.4)
  - New York City, Board of Education: Seward Park High School (Box 27, Folder 6.5)
  - New York City, Board of Estimate (Box 27, Folder 6.6)
  - New York City, Borough President (Box 27, Folder 6.7)
  - New York City, City College (Box 27, Folder 6.8)
  - New York City, Health Department (Box 27, Folder 6.9)
  - New York City, Mayor's Office (Box 27, Folder 6.10)
  - New York City, Parks Department (Box 27, Folder 6.11)
  - New York City, Police Department (Box 27, Folder 6.12)
  - New York City. Postmaster General (Box 27, Folder 6.13)
  - New York City, Welfare Department (Box 27, Folder 6.14)
  - New York City, photographs of street scenes, sweat shops, etc. (Box 27, Folder 6.15)
  - New York City Affairs Committee (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - New York City, economic conditions: J93O-1933 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - New York School of Social Work (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - New York State. departments (miscellaneous) (Box 28, Folder 4.1)
  - New York State. State Charities Aid Association (Box 28, Folder 4.2)
  - New York State, Westchester County Park Commission (Box 28, Folder 4.3)
  - New York Times (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - New York University (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - The Open Road, Inc. (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - P (miscellaneous) (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Parks and playgrounds, Central Park (Box 28, Folder 9.1)
  - Parks and playgrounds, Committee of 1000 (Box 28, Folder 9.2)
  - Parks and playgrounds, Corlears Hook (Box 28, Folder 9.3)
  - Parks and playgrounds, Delancey Street (Box 29, Folder 9.4)
    On Reel 29 of the Wald Microfilm
  - Parks and playgrounds, correspondence (Box 29, Folder 9.5)
  - Parks and playgrounds; memoranda, etc. (Box 29, Folder 9.6)
  - Parks and playgrounds, printed material (Box 29, Folder 9.7)
  - Parks and playgrounds, Parks and Playgrounds Association of the City of New York correspondence (Box 29, Folder 1.1)
  - Parks and playgrounds. Parks and Playgrounds Association of the City of New York: reports (Box 29, Folder 1.2)
  - Parks and playgrounds, Playground and Recreation Association of America (Box 29, Folder 1.3)
  - Parks and playgrounds, Rockaway (Box 29, Folder 1.4)
  - Parks and playgrounds, Seward Pack (Box 29, Folder 1.5)
  - Pensions (widows, children, old-age, etc.): correspondence (Box 29, Folder 2.1)
  - Pensions (widows, children. old-age, etc.): memoranda, reports (Box 29, Folder 2.2)
  - Pensions (widows. Children, old-age, etc.): printed materials (Box 29, Folder 2.3)
  - Pensions (widows. children. old-age. etc.): statutes in various states (Box 29, Folder 2.4)
  - The People’s Institute (Box 29, Folder 3)
    On Reel 30 of the Wald Microfilm
  - Political symposiums (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Population (congestion) (Box 29, Folder 5.1)
  - Population. census (France, Germany) (Box 29, Folder 5.2)
  - Progressive Legislation Conference (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Prisons (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Prohibition, correspondence (Box 29, Folder 8.1)
  - Prohibition. printed matter. clippings (Box 29, Folder 8.2)
  - Prohibition, printed matter: pamphlets (Box 29, Folder 8.3)
  - Prohibition, reports (Box 29, Folder 8.4)
  - Prohibition, Study by National Federation of Settlements: correspondence (Box 29, Folder 8.5)
  - Prohibition, Study by National Federation of Settlements: memoranda, etc. (Box 29, Folder 8.6)
  - Pushcart peddlers (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - R (miscellaneous) (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Radio (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Reconciliation Trips (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - "Recreational Leader" (magazine) (Box 30, Folder 5)
    On Reel 31 of the Wald Microfilm
  - Republican Party, Welfare Advisory Committee: correspondence (Box 30, Folder 6.1)
  - Republican Party, Welfare Advisory Committee: memoranda~ etc. (Box 30, Folder 6.2)
  - Rockefeller Foundation (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Rotary Club (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Rumania (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Russell Sage Foundation (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - S (miscellaneous) (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Sacco-Vanzetti (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Salvation Army (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Schiff, Jacob H.; miscellaneous (Box 30, Folder 14.1)
  - Schiff, Jacob H.; Committee on Labor Arbitration (Box 30, Folder 14.2)
  - Schiff Parkway. (Box 30, Folder 14.3)
  - Scholarships, applications (Box 30, Folder 15.1)
  - Scholarships, correspondence (Box 30, Folder 15.2)
  - Scholarships; reports, printed material, etc. (Box 30, Folder 15.3)
  - Scholarships, Alva scholarship (Box 30, Folder 15.4)
  - Silvin, Joseph (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Smith, Al (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Smith College, social work (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - Social Halls Association, Clinton Hall (general) (Box 31, Folder 1.1)
    On Reel 32 of the Wald Microfilm
  - Social Halls Association, Clinton Halt by-laws (Box 31, Folder 1.2)
  - Social Halls Association, Clinton Hall: financial statements, reports, etc. (Box 31, Folder 1.3)
  - Social Halls Association, Clinton Hall: legal papers (Box 31, Folder 1.4)
  - Social Halls Association, Clinton Hall: printed material (Box 31, Folder 1.5)
  - Social Halls Association, Clinton Hall: Rabinowitz (Box 31, Folder 1.6)
  - Social Halls Association, Clinton Hall: Secretary Cordley (Box 31, Folder 1.7)
  - Social Halls Association, Clinton Hall: stockholders lists (Box 31, Folder 1.8)
  - Social Halls Association, Clinton Hall: theater (Box 31, Folder 1.9)
  - Social Halls Association, Clinton Hall: Treasurer Brown (Box 31, Folder 1.10)
  - Social Halls Association, Clinton Hall: Treasurer Lowenstein (Box 31, Folder 1.11)
  - Social Halls Association, Clinton Hall: Treasurer Sheldon (Box 31, Folder 1.12)
  - Social Security (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Socialism, correspondence (Box 31, Folder 3.1)
  - Socialism, printed materials (Box 31, Folder 3.2)
  - Socialism, Manumit School (Box 31, Folder 3.3)
  - Socialist Party of Maine (Box 31, Folder 4)
    On Reel 33 of the Wald Microfilm
  - Society for Ethical Culture (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Street and Outdoor Cleanliness Committee, correspondence and reports (Box 31, Folder 6.1)
  - Street and Outdoor Cleanliness Committee, printed materials (Box 31, Folder 6.2)
  - 'The Survey Graphic· (magazine), 1925-1926 (Box 32, Folder 1.1)
  - 'The Survey Graphic· (magazine), 1927 (Box 32, Folder 1.2)
  - "The Survey Graphic-(magazine), 1978 (Box 32, Folder 1.3)
  - 'The Survey Graphic" (magazine), 1929-1930 (Box 32, Folder 1.4)
  - 'The Survey Graphic" (magazine), 1931 (Box 32, Folder 1.5)
  - 'The Survey Graphic· (magazine), 1932-1933 (Box 32, Folder 1.6)
  - T (miscellaneous) (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Teachers College, Columbia University (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Thomas. Norman (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - The Threefold Movement (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Town Hall Club (Roll of Honor) (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Travelers Aid Society (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - U (miscellaneous) (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Unemployment, 1909-1931 (Box 32, Folder 9.1)
  - Unemployment. 1932-193S (Box 32, Folder 9.2)
    On Reel 34 of the Wald Microfilm
  - Unemployment, Mayor's Committee: 1916-1917 (Box 32, Folder 9.3)
  - Unemployment, Peoples League (of New York) (Box 32, Folder 9.4)
  - Unemployment, printed materials (Box 32, Folder 9.5)
  - Unemployment insurance (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - United States Army, longevity claims (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - "The United States Daily· (magazine) (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - United States Government, departments (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - V (miscellaneous) (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Variety Products Co. (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Vassar College (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Vocational Adjustment Bureau (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Vocational Bureau. Inc. (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Vocational guidance, correspondence (Box 33, Folder 6.1)
  - Vocational guidance; memoranda, etc. (Box 33, Folder 6.2)
  - Vocational guidance, minutes (Box 33, Folder 6.3)
  - Vocational guidance. New York City departments (Box 33, Folder 6.4)
  - Vocational guidance. printed materials (Box 33, Folder 6.5)
  - Vocational Guidance Bureau (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Vocational Service for Juniors. 1921-1925 (Box 33, Folder 8.1)
    On Reel 35 of the Wald Microfilm
  - Vocational Service for Juniors. 1926-1928 (Box 33, Folder 8.2)
  - Vocational Service for Juniors, 1929-1932 (Box 33, Folder 8.3)
  - W (miscellaneous) (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Welch. William Henry (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Welfare Council. correspondence: 1925 (Box 33, Folder 11.1)
  - Welfare Council. correspondence: 1926 (Box 33, Folder 11.2)
  - Welfare Council. correspondence: 1927 (Box 33, Folder 11.3)
  - Welfare Council. correspondence: 1928 (Box 33, Folder 11.4)
  - Welfare Council, correspondence: 1929 (Box 33, Folder 11.5)
  - Welfare Council. correspondence; 1930 (Box 33, Folder 11.6)